<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>  on Can Suyolcu</title>
    <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in   on Can Suyolcu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Keras API</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>I will be using a subset of the LendingClub DataSet obtained from Kaggle.
LendingClub is a US peer-to-peer lending company, headquartered in San Francisco, California. It was the first peer-to-peer lender to register its offerings as securities with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), and to offer loan trading on a secondary market. LendingClub is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest peer-to-peer lending platform.
Given historical data on loans given out with information on whether or not the borrower defaulted (charge-off),I will build a model that can predict whether or not a borrower will pay back their loan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>In this NLP project I will be attempting to classify Yelp Reviews into 1 star or 5 star categories based off the text content in the reviews.
I will be using Yelp Review Data Set from Kaggle.
Each observation in this dataset is a review of a particular business by a particular user.
The &amp;ldquo;stars&amp;rdquo; column is the number of stars (1 through 5) assigned by the reviewer to the business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Recommendation Systems</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>For this project I will use recommendation system to find similar movies to Star Wars and Liar Liar.
  Github link to this project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: K Means Clustering</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>For this project I will attempt to use KMeans Clustering to cluster Universities into to two groups, Private and Public. It is very important to note, I actually have the labels for this data set, but I will NOT use them for the KMeans clustering algorithm, since that is an unsupervised learning algorithm. I will use the labels to try to get an idea of how well the algorithm performed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: IRIS Dataset</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>I will be analyzing the famous iris data set using support vector machines. The Iris flower data set or Fisher&amp;rsquo;s Iris data set is a multivariate data set introduced by Sir Ronald Fisher in the 1936 as an example of discriminant analysis. The data set consists of 50 samples from each of three species of Iris (Iris setosa, Iris virginica and Iris versicolor), so 150 total samples. Four features were measured from each sample: the length and the width of the sepals and petals, in centimeters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>For this project I will be exploring publicly available data from LendingClub.com. I use lending data from 2007-2010 and be trying to classify and predict whether or not the borrower paid back their loan in full.
Here are what the columns represent:
 credit.policy: 1 if the customer meets the credit underwriting criteria of LendingClub.com, and 0 otherwise. purpose: The purpose of the loan (takes values &amp;ldquo;credit_card&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;debt_consolidation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;educational&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;major_purchase&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;small_business&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;all_other&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: KNN</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>In this project I worked with a classified data set from a company. This will be a simple project in order to classify the target class.
  Github link to this project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>In this project I worked with the Titanic Data Set from Kaggle. I tried to predict a classification- survival or deceased implementing Logistic Regression in Python for classification.
  Github link to this project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>In this project I&amp;rsquo;ll be using linear regression in order to decide for a company whether to focus their efforts on a mobile app experience or a website.
  Github link to this project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: 911 Calls</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This is an exercise project in order to practice my Pandas, NumPy, Seaborn and Matplotlib skills in Python.
For this capstone project I will be analyzing some 911 call data from Kaggle.
  Github link to this project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Financial Crisis</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>In this data project I focus on exploratory data analysis of stock prices and see how they progressed throughout the financial crisis all the way to early 2016.
  Github link to this project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cansuyolcu.github.io/science/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can follow me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/can-suyolcu-0a330a190/   Medium: https://medium.com/@can.suyolcu95   Github: https://github.com/CanSuyolcu    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>